700 N. Woodlawn Ave. Luddy Hall, Bloomington, IN, 47404

Summary _

PhD candidate in Intelligent Systems Engineering department in Luddy School of Informatics, Computing, and Engineering at Indiana University Bloomington. I investigate efficient machine learning and deep learning solutions for audio processing problems with my advisor Prof. Minje Kim. My current research focuses on novel modes of compression for source separation applications through personalization and scalable learning for practical deployment onto resource-constrained devices.

Positions Held

Indiana University Bloomington, IN

RESEARCH ASSISTANT Dec 2018 - Present

- · Funded by NSF project "A Portable and Intelligent Testing System for Power-efficient and Accurate Foodborne Pathogen Detection"
- · Researching efficient machine learning and deep learning models through various modes of model compression

Amazon Lab126 Sunnyvale, CA (Remote)

APPLIED SCIENTIST INTERN

- Group: Audio Technology
- Supervisors: Mrudula Athi, Guangji Shi, Trausti Kristjansson
- · Project: Personalized speech dereverberation

Amazon Lab126 Sunnyvale, CA (Remote)

APPLIED SCIENTIST INTERN May. 2020 - Aug 2020

- Group: Audio Technology
- Supervisors: Yuzhou Liu, Krishna Kamath, Trausti Kristjansson
- · Project: Model compression for speech enhancement

Qualcomm San Diego, CA

INTERIM ENGINEERING INTERN May. 2019 - Aug 2019

- · Group: Audio Algorithms
- Supervisors: Shuhua Zhang, Laehoon Kim
- Project: Non-linear echo cancellation

Indiana University Bloomington, IN

TEACHING ASSISTANT • Deep Learning Systems [Spring 2018]

- Machine Learning for Signal Processing [Fall 2017, Fall 2018]
- Software Engineering [Fall 2016, Spring 2017]

National Center for Supercomputing Applications Urbana, IL

CYBERGIS SPIN INTERN May. 2015 - May 2016

Parallel Terrain Analysis and predictive ecosystem mapping

Publications

BLOOM-Net: Blockwise Optimization for Masking Networks Toward Scalable and Efficient Speech Enhancement

SUNWOO KIM, MINJE KIM (UNDER REVIEW) May 22-27, 2022

International Conference on Acoustics, Speech, and Signal Processing (ICASSP)

Test-Time Adaptation Toward Personalized Speech Enhancement: Zero-Shot Learning with Knowledge Distillation

SUNWOO KIM, MINJE KIM Oct 17-20, 2021

IEEE Workshop on Applications of Signal Processing to Audio and Acoustics (WASPAA)

Personalized Speech Enhancement through Self-Supervised Data Augmentation and **Purification**

Aug 30 - Sep 3, 2021 ASWIN SIVARAMAN, SUNWOO KIM, MINJE KIM

Interspeech

Boosted Locality Sensitive Hashing: Discriminative Binary Codes For Source Separation

Barcelona, Spain (Remote) SUNWOO KIM, HAICI YANG, MINJE KIM (NOMINATED FOR THE BEST STUDENT PAPER AWARD)

International Conference on Acoustics, Speech, and Signal Processing (ICASSP)

SUNWOO KIM · RÉSUMÉ NOVEMBER 17, 2021

Brno, Czech Republic (Remote)

New Paltz, NY (Remote)

May 4-8, 2020

Jun. 2021 - Sep 2021

Aug. 2016 - Dec 2018

Singapore

Incremental Binarization On Recurrent Neural Networks For Single-Channel Source Separation

Brighton, UK

SUNWOO KIM, MRINMOY MAITY, MINJE KIM

International Conference on Acoustics, Speech, and Signal Processing (ICASSP)

May 12-17, 2019

Urbana, IL

Education

Indiana University

Bloomington, IN

Ph.D. Candidate in Intelligent Systems Engineering

Aug 2016 - May 2022 (expected)

Advised by professor Minje Kim

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign

B.S. IN PHYSICS May 2016

Academic Services

IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech, and Signal Processing (ICASSP)

 CONFERENCE REVIEWER
 2020, 2021, 2022

IEEE Transactions on Audio, Speech and Language Proceedings (TASLP)

JOURNAL REVIEWER 2021

European Association for Signal Processing (EURASIP) Journal on Audio, Speech, and Music Processing

JOURNAL REVIEWER 2019, 2020, 2021

Technical and Personal skills

Programming

PYTHON, C++, JAVA, R, MATLAB, BASH SCRIPTING

Software and Tools

TENSORFLOW, PyTorch, Keras, Kaldi

Languages

Fluent in Korean and English. Able to understand basic Chinese (Mandarin)